Atul Meshram

Product Designer

https://atulmeshram.github.io

+91-8050606549

m.atulmeshram@gmail.com

Bangalore, Karnataka - INDIA

Education

- **Interaction Design Specialization** University of California, San Diego 9.9 Score | Jan, 2018 | Coursera
- Master of Computer Applications NIT Karnataka, Surathkal 8.5 CGPA | May, 2016
- **GNIIT Software Engineering** NTTT

Grade - A | Apr, 2013

Bachelor of Computer Applications PRSU, Raipur 78.0% | Jun, 2011

Class 12th (Senior Secondary Edu.) CBSE - All India 81.0% | May, 2007

Skills

Design Tools

InVision Studio Sketch Adobe XD Figma

FramerX Adobe After Effects ProtoPie Adobe Illustrator

Blender Flinto

User Experience

UX Research Interaction Design Wireframing Motion Design Rapid Prototyping Visual Design Heuristic Evaluation A/B Testing **Usability Testing** Comparative Analysis

Programming

JavaScript (ES6) Flutter HTML5 **ThreeJS** CSS3 **GSAP** ReactJS VueJS

Leadership

Project Planning UX Strategy & Planning Team Coordination Training & Mentorship

Summary

Product designer with 4.6+ years of user-centric design experience. I enjoy interacting with people, understand their expectations and displeasing experiences from the products, and use their insights to create simple and intuitive interfaces that have a high degree of usability. Interested in immersive design and extended reality-based emerging technologies.

Experience

o9 Solutions

Bengaluru, IN

Senior UX Designer

[MAY, 2018 - Present]

- Designed and prototyped, multiple widgets and features for web, mobile, and desktop applications varying from small, one-week prototypes that explored specific interactions to large-scale, multi-month projects targeted for the launch.
- Designed intuitive, interactive, and smart analytical visual interface for the AI-based smart supply-chain platform offering features like:

Natural Language Search, Rich Data Visualization, Real-Time Collaboration, Connected Excel, Mobile Experience, Integrated Email, Geo Map & Network, Online Meeting and Presentation, and Favorite Management.

Case Study: https://atulmeshram.github.io/o9-solutions.html

Accolite Software

Bengaluru, IN

UX Designer

[JUL, 2016 - MAR, 2018]

Worked for various clients at client locations. Analyzed, prototyped, and delivered the designs as per client's design requirements.

Standard Chartered Banking App [NOV, 2017 - MAR, 2018]

A mobile app for managing finances anytime anywhere.

Designed UI to offer UPI based transactions to facilitate safe, easy & instant digital payments.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/ryNkoPX

FedEx FRMS iPad App

[SEP 2017 - NOV 2017]

An iPad app for FedEx's Pilot Fatigue Management.

Analyzed existing web application and redesigned the workflow for the app.

Designed high-fidelity clickable prototypes, UI design assets distribution, application flow, animations, and design guide for the developers.

BT Business App

[JUL 2016 - OCT 2017]

A business service mobile app for users offering with features to view bills, check accounts, test broadband speed, track orders, and faults.

User-research, analysis, and interpretation of customer needs, to create a pleasant user experience. Designed application flow, created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups.

Google Play Store: https://cutt.ly/8yNkbU2 **Apple App Store:** https://cutt.ly/kyNkRFY

